<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="hyprlauncher_core" version="1">
  <copyright>
    BSD 3-Clause License

    Copyright (c) 2025, Hypr Development

    Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
    modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions are met:

    1. Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice, this
        list of conditions and the following disclaimer.

    2. Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright notice,
        this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the documentation
        and/or other materials provided with the distribution.

    3. Neither the name of the copyright holder nor the names of its
        contributors may be used to endorse or promote products derived from
        this software without specific prior written permission.

    THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS "AS IS"
    AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE
    IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE
    DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDER OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE
    FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL
    DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR
    SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER
    CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY,
    OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE
    OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.
  </copyright>

  <object name="hyprlauncher_core_manager" version="1">
    <description summary="manager object">
      This is the core manager object for hyprlauncher operations
    </description>

    <c2s name="set_open_state">
      <description summary="Set the launcher's open state">
            Sets the open state of the launcher.
            0 - toggle
            1 - open
            2 - close
      </description>
      <arg name="state" type="uint" summary="open state"/>
    </c2s>

    <c2s name="open_with_options">
      <description summary="Open the launcher with options">
            Opens the launcher with given options. If the launcher
            is already open, this is a no-op.
      </description>
      <arg name="options" type="array varchar" summary="option array"/>
    </c2s>

    <c2s name="get_info_object">
      <description summary="Get launcher's info object">
            Gets the launcher info object. That object will return some data about
            the launcher's state
      </description>
      <returns iface="hyprlauncher_core_info"/>
    </c2s>

    <c2s name="destroy" destructor="true">
      <description summary="Destroy this object">
            Destroys this object. Children remain alive until destroyed.
      </description>
    </c2s>
  </object>

  <object name="hyprlauncher_core_info" version="1">
    <description summary="manager object">
      Info object, will emit various information about the state of the launcher
    </description>

    <s2c name="open_state">
      <description summary="Open the launcher with options">
            Emitted on creation of this object, and when the state changes.
      </description>
      <arg name="state" type="uint" summary="open state"/>
    </s2c>

    <s2c name="selection_made">
      <description summary="Selection was made">
            Emitted on selection by the user. The launcher will close immediately
            after this is emitted.
      </description>
      <arg name="selected" type="varchar" summary="selected entry"/>
    </s2c>

    <c2s name="destroy" destructor="true">
      <description summary="Destroy this object">
            Destroys this object. Children remain alive until destroyed.
      </description>
    </c2s>
  </object>
</protocol>
